<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>19</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>32</p>
<p>United States as a scene of profitable enterprise, but
of the general character and manners of its inhabitants.
But what is his representation of the nature of slavery, 
and its effects on the more and intellectual qualities
of the American population ?  Let the friends and 
advocates of our slave-system, and, above all, let our
members of Parliament, who may be called to revise 
that system, weight it well.  It is replete with consider-
ations of momentous import.  The passage will be found 
in Birbeck's "Notes," p. 20.</p>
<p>" May 10. I saw two female slaves and their 
children sold by auction in the street; an incident of 
common occurence here, though horrifying to myself
and many other strangers.  I could hardly bear to see
them handled and examined like cattle; and when I
heard their sobs, and saw the big tears roll down their
cheeks at the thoughs of being separated, I could not 
refrain from weeping with them.  In selling these un-
happy beings, little regards is had to the parting of the
nearest relations. <placeName key="Virginia, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Virginia&amp;params=37.5_N_79_W_region:US-VA_type:adm1st_scale:3000000">Virginia</placeName> prides itself on the com-
parative mildness of its treatment of the slaves; and, in
fact, they increase in numbers, many being annually
supplies from this state to those further south, where
the treatment is said to be much more severe. There
are regular dealers who buy them up, and drive them
in gangs, chained together, to a southern  market. I
am informed, that a few weeks pass without some of them Hw ' ~
being marched through this place. A traveller told me,
that he saw, two weeks ago, one hdndred and twenty
sold by auction in the streets of <placeName key="Richmond, Virginia, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Richmond%2C_Virginia&amp;params=37_32_N_77_28_W_region:US-VA_type:city">Richmond</placeName>; and that
they filled the air with their lamentiations.
 </p>
<p>
    "It has also been conﬁdently alleged, that the con-
dition of slaves in <placeName key="Virginia, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Virginia&amp;params=37.5_N_79_W_region:US-VA_type:adm1st_scale:3000000">Virginia</placeName>, under the mild treatment 
    they are siad to experience, is preferrable to that of our
    English labourers. I know and lament the degrading 
    state of dependent poverty to which the latter have
  
 been gradually reduced by the operation of laws origin-
ally designed for their comfort and protection. I know
also that many slaves pass their lives in comparutive
ease, and seem to be unconcious of their bonds, and   
    that the <i>most wretched</i> of our paupers might envy the 
allotment of the <i>happy</i> Negro. This is not, however, 
institutind a fair comparison, to bring the opposite ex-
tremes of the two classes into competition. Let us take
a view of some particulars which operate generally.
</p>
<p>
“ In <placeName key="England" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=England&amp;params=51_30_N_0_7_W_type:city">England</placeName>, exertion is not the result of personal
fear in <placeName key="Virginia, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Virginia&amp;params=37.5_N_79_W_region:US-VA_type:adm1st_scale:3000000">Virginia</placeName>, it is the prevailing stimulus.
</p>
<p>
“ The slave is punished for mere <i>indolence</i>, at the
discretion of an <i>overseer</i>: the peasant is only punished
by the law, when guilty of a crime.
</p>
<p>
“ In <placeName key="England" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=England&amp;params=51_30_N_0_7_W_type:city">England</placeName>, the labourer and his employer ere
equal in the eye of the law : here the law affords the
slave no protection, unless a White man gives testimony
in his favour.
</p>
<p>
"Here, any White man may insult a Black with im-
punity; whilst the English peasant, should he receive a
blow from his employer, might and would return it with
interest and afterwards have his remedy at law for the
aggression.
</p>
<p>
“ The testimony of a peasant weighs as much as that
of a lord in a court of justice; but the testimony of a
slave is never admitted at all, in a case where a White
man is opposed to him. 
</p>
<p>
“ A few weeks ago, in the streets of <placeName key="Richmond, Virginia, United States" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Richmond%2C_Virginia&amp;params=37_32_N_77_28_W_region:US-VA_type:city">Richmond</placeName>, a
friend of mine saw a White boy wontonly throw quick-
lime in the face of a Negro-man.  The man shook the
lime from his jacket, and some of it accidentally reached 
the eyes of the young brute.  This casual retaliation
excited the resentment of the brother of the boy, who
   complained to the slave's owner, and actually had him
    punished with thirty lashes.  This would not have hap-
    pended to an English peasant.
 </p>
<p>D</p>


            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
